Preliminary Guide to the Kenneth M. Johnson Sermons, 1951-2002
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Kenneth M. Johnson Sermons 1951-2002
Johnson, Kenneth M., 1928-
10.3 linear feet Extent: 4916 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.00638
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Kenneth M. Johnson Sermons were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2001-2002.
Biographical Note
Retired United Methodist minister.
Collection Overview
Typescripts of sermons (01-179) (652 items, 4.5 linear feet; dated 1951-1977), many containing handwritten notes and accompanying material on which the sermon topic was based. Sermons are numbered and are arranged by date, according to the church Johnson was serving at the time. Churches include McKendree Chapel, New Mt. Vernon-Shady Grove, West Bend, Oak Summit, Asbury Memorial, and Green Street.
Typescripts of sermons (02-038) (401 items, 2.6 linear feet; dated 1971-1988); content and arrangement are the same as that in the initial accession. North Carolina churches Johnson served include Saint Andrew's (Charlotte), Central (Mooresville), Leaksville (Eden), First (Newton), and Burkhead (Winston-Salem).
Typescripts and card indexes of sermons (02-140) (ca. 3863 items, 3.2 linear feet; dated 1984-2002). Content and arrangement of sermons (263 items) are the same as in previous accessions, except this addition includes sermons preached during Johnson's retirement (1995-2002). North Carolina churches Johnson served include Burkhead Methodist (Winston-Salem), Aldersgate Methodist (Shelby), and Grace Methodist (Greensboro). Johnson also preached several sermons in Indonesia (1995, 1998). The card index (ca. 3600 items) arranges sermons by title, topic, and scriptures and texts.
Subject Headings
Johnson, Kenneth M., 1928-; Sermons, American; Sermons, American -- 20th century; Sermons, American -- North Carolina; Methodist Church -- Sermons -- 20th century; Methodist Church -- North Carolina; Sermons; Indexes (reference sources)
Contents of Collection
- Accession 2001-0179
  - Sermons 1951-1957 (Box 1)
    - Nos. 1-28 Statesville District: McKendree Charge (McKendree Chapel, Williamson's Chapel, Rocky Mount), 1951-1952 (Box 1)
    - Nos. 29-115 Thomasville District: New Mt. Vernon-Shady Grove Charge, 1952-1955 (Box 1)
    - Nos. 116-118 Asheboro, NC: West Bend Methodist, 1955-1960 (Box 1)
  - Sermons 1957-1977 (Box 2)
    - Nos. 119-238 Asheboro, NC: West Bend Methodist (cont.), 1955-1960 (Box 2)
  - Sermons 1955-1960 (Box 3)
    - Nos. 239-333 Asheboro, NC: West Bend Methodist (cont.), 1955-1960 (Box 3)
  - Sermons 1955-1964 (Box 4)
    - Nos. 334-350 Asheboro, NC: West Bend Methodist (cont.), 1955-1960 (Box 4)
    - Nos. 351-424 Winston-Salem, NC: Oak Summit Methodist, 1960-1964 (Box 4)
  - Sermons 1960-1967 (Box 5)
    - Nos. 425-466 Winston-Salem, NC: Oak Summit Methodist (cont.), 1960-1964 (Box 5)
    - Nos. 467-519 Asheville, NC: Asbury Memorial Methodist, 1964-1967 (Box 5)
  - Sermons 1964-1971 (Box 6)
    - Nos. 520-541 Asheville, NC: Asbury Memorial Methodist (cont.), 1964-1967 (Box 6)
    - Nos. 542-614 Winston-Salem, NC: Green Street Methodist, 1967-1971 (Box 6)
  - Sermons 1967-1971 (Box 7)
    - Nos. 615-647 Winston-Salem, NC: Green Street Methodist (cont.), 1967-1971 (Box 7)
- Accession 2002-0038
  - Sermons, 1971-1977 (Box 1)
    - Nos. 648-687 Charlotte, NC: Saint Andrew's United Methodist, 1971-1974 (Box 1)
    - Nos. 688-732 Mooresville, NC: Central United Methodist, 1974-1977 (Box 1)
  - Sermons, 1974-1981 (Box 2)
    - Nos. 733-762 Mooresville, NC: Central United Methodist (cont.) 1974-1977 (Box 2)
    - Nos. 763-833 Eden, NC: Leaksville United Methodist, 1977-1981 (Box 2)
  - Sermons, 1977-1984 (Box 3)
    - Nos. 834-886 Eden, NC: Leaksville United Methodist (cont.), 1977-1981 (Box 3)
    - Nos. 887-926 Newton, NC: First United Methodist, 1981-1984 (Box 3)
  - Sermons, 1981-1988 (Box 4)
    - Nos. 927-992 Newton, NC: First United Methodist (cont.), 1981-1984 (Box 4)
    - Nos. 993-1032 Winston-Salem, NC: Burkhead United Methodist, 1984-1988 (Box 4)
  - Sermons, 1984-1988 (Box 5)
    - Nos. 1033-1049 Winston-Salem, NC: Burkhead United Methodist, 1984-1988 (Box 5)
- Accession 2002-0140
  - Sermons, 1985-1988 (Box 1)
    - Nos. 1050-1150 Winston-Salem, NC: Burkhead Methodist, 1985-1988 (Box 1)
    - Nos. 1151-1164 Shelby, NC: Aldersgate Methodist, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Sermons, 1988-1991 (Box 2)
    - Nos. 1165-1238 Shelby, NC: Aldersgate Methodist, 1988-1990 (Box 2)
    - Nos. 1239-1274 Greensboro, NC: Grace Methodist, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - Sermons, 1991-1993 (Box 3)
    - Nos. 1275-1380 Greensboro, NC: Grace Methodist, 1991-1993 (Box 3)
  - Sermons, 1993-2002 (Box 4)
    - Nos. 1381-1418 Greensboro, NC: Grace Methodist, 1993-1994 (Box 4)
    - Nos. 1419-1434 Medan, N. Sumatra, Indonesia, 1995 January-April (Box 4)
    - No. 1435 Rocky Mount, NC: Rocky Mount UMC, 1995 August 20 (Box 4)
    - No. 1436 Newton, NC: First Baptist Church, 1996 May 26 (Box 4)
    - No. 1437 Winston-Salem, NC: Green Street UMC, 1996 May 19 (Box 4)
    - No. 1438 Charlotte, NC: Pleasant Grove UMC, 1996 September 8 (Box 4)
    - No. 1439 Winston-Salem, NC: Oak Summit UMC, 1997 May 18 (Box 4)
    - No. 1440 Enka, NC: Francis Asbury UMC, 1997 June 29 (Box 4)
    - No. 1441 Haverhill, NH: First Congregational, 1997 August 10 1997 (Box 4)
    - No. 1442 Asheville, NC: Asbury Memorial, 1997 October 12 (Box 4)
    - Nos. 1443-1449 Jakarta, Indonesia, 1998 April-May (Box 4)
    - Nos. 1450-1452 Indonesia: Prepared but not preached, 1998 May (Box 4)
    - No. 1453 Haverhill, NH: First Congregational, 1999 August 1 (Box 4)
    - No. 1454 Bel Air, MD: Bel Air UMC, 1999 October 17 (Box 4)
    - No. 1455 Horse Shoe, NC: Cummings Memorial UMC, 2000 August 1 (Box 4)
    - No. 1456 Charlotte, NC: Pleasant Grove, 2001 September 9 (Box 4)
    - No. 1457 Holly Springs, GA: Holly Springs UMC, 2001 September 16 (Box 4)
    - No. 1458 Asheboro, NC: West Bend UMC, 2002 May 19 (Box 4)
  - Card index to sermons (Box 5)
    - By title, A-W (Box 5)
  - Card index to sermons (Box 6)
    - By title, X-Z (Box 6)
    - By topic, A-G(Good works) (Box 6)
  - Card index to sermons (Box 7)
    - By topic, G(Goodbye)-P(Prostitution) (Box 7)
  - Card index to sermons (Box 8)
    - By topic, P(Protection)-Z (Box 8)
    - By scriptures and texts, Genesis-John (Box 8)
  - Card index to sermons (Box 9)
    - By scriptures and texts, Genesis-John, continued; Acts-Revelation (Box 9)